Mss.B.G784
American Philosophical Society
- Papers
  - Letter to [John E. Gray], Oct. 23, 1839; 9x7-1/4; Babington, Charles Cardale, 1808-1895
    Cambridge, A.L.S. 2p. Has searched for the shell, due to Henslow's request.
  - Letter to Mrs. [Maria Emma] Gray, Dec. 16, 1839; 9x7-1/2; Airy, George Biddell, Sir, 1801-1892
    A.L.S. 2p. and add. Concerning astronomical observations.
  - Letter to [John E. Gray], Aug. 9, 184-; 7x4-1/4; Eskleben, J.
    L. 1p. Forwards plate.
  - Letter to John Edward Gray?, 1840 January 7; Lee, John
  - Letter to [John E. Gray], Jan. 9, 1840; 7-1/4x4-1/2; Broderip, William John, 1789-1859
    A.L.S. 1p. Asks name of opossum.
  - Letter to E[dward] W[illiam] Gray, Jan. 20, 1840; 4-3/4x4-1/2; Faraday, Michael, 1791-1867
    A.L.S. 1p. May join him February 14.
  - Letter to John Edward Gray, 1840 February 17; Stephens, Henry Oxley
  - Letter to John Edward Gray, 1840? February 21
  - Letter to John Edward Gray, 1840 March 19; Wyse?, Thomas
  - Letter to [John E.] Gray, April 3, 1840; 7-1/4x4-1/2; Benton, Edward
    A.L.S. 3p. Congratulates him on his new post.
  - Letter to John E. Gray, April 5, 1840; 4-1/2x3-3/4; Carpenter, William Benjamin, 1813-1885
    Bristol, A.L.S. 3p. and add. Congratulates him on his new post. Explains a publication.
  - Letter to [John E.] Gray, April 8, 1840; 7-1/4x4-1/2; Baber, Henry Hervey, 1775-1869
    A.L.S. 2p. Congratulates him on his appointment at the British Museum.
  - Letter to "My dear Sir", April 29, 1840; Gray, John Edward, 1800-1875
  - Letter to J[ohn] E. Gray, London, June 18, 1840; 9x7-1/4; Elliot, Walter, Sir, 1803-1887
    A.L.S. 4p., add. Cannot do much collecting, but sends him a snake for the British museum.
  - Letter to J[ohn] E. Gray, Sept. 1, 1840; 7-1/2x4-1/2; Clift, William, 1775-1849
    A.L.S. 1p. Introduces a man interested in mollusks.
  - Letter to J[ohn] B. Gray, Nov. 11, 1840; 6x4; Bourne, John
    A.L.S. 2p. Will welcome them for a visit.
  - Letter to Mrs. [Maria Emma] Gray, Dec. 30, 1840; 7x4-1/2; Children, John George, 1777-1852
    A.L.S. 1p. Invitation to dinner.
  - Letter to John Edward Gray, 1841? January 6; Ogilby, William
  - Letter to Mrs. John Edward Gray, 1841 January 11; Yolland?, N.
  - Letter to John Edward Gray?, 1841 February 8; Solly, Samuel
  - Letter to John Edward Gray, 1841 February 15; Jones, Thomas Rymer
  - Letter to J[ohn] E. Gray, Feb. 16, 1841; 9-1/4x7; Microscopical society of London
    A.L.S.: Arthur Farre. 1p. Announces his election as a member of the council.
  - Letter to John Edward Gray?, 1841 February 23; Hodgson, Joseph
  - Letter to John Edward Gray, 1841 March 13; Prosser, George Walter?
  - Letter to J[ohn] E. Gray, March 20, 1841; 7-1/4x4-1/2; Airy, George Biddell, Sir, 1801-1892
    Greenwich, A.L.S. 1p. Thanks for his last note, which he will answer.
  - Letter to John Edward Gray, 1841 April 6; Kay, J. Taylor
  - Letter to John Edward Gray?, 1841 April 19; Paget, James, Sir
  - Letter to Mrs. [Maria Emma] Gray, May 3, 1841; 7-1/4x4-1/4; Bowman, William, Sir, 1816-1892
    A.L.S. 1p. Cannot accept the invitation. May see her at the British museum before he leaves town.
  - Letter to John Edward Gray, 1841 May 8; Jackson, ?
  - Letter to J[ohn] E. Gray, May 15, 1841; 9x7; Gilbertson, William
    Preston, A.L.S. 1p. Forwards fossils.
  - Letter to John Edward Gray?, 1841 May 19; [Smith, J. C.]?
  - Letter to Sir Henry Ellis, May 31, 1841; 7-1/4x4-3/4; Dyce, William, 1806-1864
    A.L.S. 1p., end. by Ellis to J. E. Gray. Asks him to let a boy copy birds.
  - Letter to John Edward Gray, 1841 May 31; Osler, Abraham Follett, 1808-1903; Wickenden, Joseph
  - Letter to John Edward Gray, 1841 June 8; Hawkings, Edward
  - Letter to John Edward Gray, 1841 June 9; King, Richard
  - Letter to Mrs. [Maria Emma] Gray, London, June 22, 1841; 8x6; Bowman, William, Sir, 1816-1892
    Paris, A.L.S. 3p. and add. Reassures her of the health of her nephew.
  - Letter to J[ohn] E. Gray, London, June 24, 1841; 7-1/4x4-3/4; Barclay, R.
    Kew, A.L.S. 3p., end. and add. Concerning natural history.
  - Letter to J[ohn] E. Gray, June 26, 1841; 7x4-1/2; Britton, John, 1771-1857
    A.L.S. 1p. Cannot accept invitation.
  - Letter to ----, July 23, 1841; 7-1/2x4-3/4; Burnett, William, Sir, 1779-1861
    A.L.S. 1p., end. Asks him to Check with Gray to see if the boxes are there.
  - Letter to J[ohn] E. Gray, Sept. 1, 1841; 7x4-1/2; Earl, Percy
    A.L.S. 4p. Concerning methods of collecting natural history specimens.
  - Letter to [John E. Gray], Dec. 6, 1841; 9x7-1/4; Cumming, James, 1777-1861
    Cambridge, A.L.S. 1p. Thanks for the tortoises.
  - Letter to John Edward Gray, Jan. 13, 1842; 7x4-1/2; Burney, Charles Parr
    A.L.S. 1p. Has promised his vote to someone else.
  - Letter to [John E. Gray], April 13, 1842; 7-3/4x5; Leemans, Conrad, 1809-1893
    Leyden, A.L.S. 4p. Introduces a friend who is interested in natural history. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to [John E.] Gray, April 25, 1842; 2-3/4x4; Duffinback
    A.L. in 3rd. P. 1p. Accepts invitation.
  - Letter to John Edward Gray?, 1842 April 28; Sopwith, Thomas
  - Letter to [John] E. Gray, April 30, 1842; 7-1/2x4-1/2; Cross, E.
    A.L.S. 2p. Concerning natural history specimens.
  - Letter to John Edward Gray?, 1842 May 12; Hutton, William
  - Concerning Emma and Henrie Cajander, June 16, 1842; 4-1/2x6; Branting, Gabr
    Stockholm, A.D.S. 1p.
  - Letter to C. Vowell, 1842 June 16; Lefroy, John Henry, Sir
  - Letter to J[ohn E.] Gray, June 20, 1842; 7-1/4x4-1/2; Brockedon, William, 1787-1854
    A.L.S. 1p. Forwards item.
  - Letter to John Edward Gray, 1842 July 6; Sowerby, James de Carle, 1787-1871
  - Letter to John Edward Gray?, 1842 July 13; Sutherland, Alexander Robert
  - Letter to [John E. Gray], Sept. 17, 1842; 7-1/4x4-1/2; Busk, Geo[rge], 1807-1886
    A.L.S. 2p. Concerning worms and shells.
  - Letter to Mrs. John Edward Gray, 1842 October 14; Smith, John Pye, 1774-1851
  - Letter to Mrs. [Maria Emma] Gray, Oct. 15, 1842; 8-3/4x7-1/4; Ellis, Henry, Sir, 1777-1869
    A.L.S. 1p. Thanks for gift.
  - Letter to [Edward] Hawkins, Nov. 2, 1842; 6-3/4x4-1/2; Etty, William, 1787-1849
    A.L.S. 1p., end. Asks favor.
  - Letter to [John E. Gray], Nov. 5, 1842; 5x3-1/2; Edwards, Frederic S.
    A.L.S. 2p. Informs him of a meeting.
  - Letter to John Edward Gray, 1842 November 8; Hancock, J.
  - Letter to [John E. Gray], Nov. 12, 1842; 5x4; Grant, J. C.
    A.L.S. 1p. Gives address of W. E. Hickson.
  - Letter to John Edward Gray, 1842 November 22; Pettigrew, Thomas Joseph
  - Letter to John Edward Gray, 1843 January 14; Heywood, James
  - Letter to [John E. Gray], Jan. 16, 1843; 7-1/2x5; Gower, J. R.
    A.L.S. 1p. Will accept his offer for birds.
  - Letter to John Edward Gray, 1843 February 3; Phillips, Henry, Jr.
  - Letter to John Edward Gray, 1843 February 15; Inglis, Robert Harry, Sir
  - Letter to Mrs. M[aria] E[mma] Gray, British Museum, Feb. 21, 1843; 8-1/2x6; Leemans, Conrad, 1809-1893
    Leyden, A.L.S. 4p., add. Contrary to report, is alive and well. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to John Edward Gray, 1843 March 2; Hassa?, Arthur H.
  - Letter to John Edward Gray, 1843 April 5; Saunders, W. Wilson, (William Wilson), 1809-1879
  - Letter to [John E. Gray], April 7, 1843; 7-1/2x4-1/2; Chesney, Francis Rawdon, 1789-1872
    Woolwich, A.L.S. 3p. and add. Asks name of bird which inhabits the Bosphorus.
  - Letter to Mr. & Mrs. Gray, April 28, 1843; 7x4-1/2; Binning
  - Letter to J[ohn] E. Gray, May 20, 1843; 8x5-1/2; Arnott, Neil, 1788-1874
    A.L.S. 2p. Introduces [Arvid August?] Afzelius.
  - Letter to [John] E. Gray, May 31, 1843; 4-1/2x3-3/4; Britton, John, 1771-1857
    Forwards volumes.
  - Letter to John Edward Gray, 1843 June 11; Hamilton, ?
  - Letter to John E. Gray, London, July 15, 1843; 4-3/4x4; Matthes, C. J.
    A.L.S. 3p. Inquires of family news. Introduces van Rees.
  - Letter to [Mrs. Maria Emma Gray], Oct. 27, 1843; 8x6-1/2; Desessus, Benjamin
    A.L. in 3rd. P. 1p. In French. Concerning shells.
  - Letter to [John E.] Gray, Nov. 17, 1843; 5-1/4x3-1/2; Fryer, J. H.
    A.L.S. 2p. Introduces a friend who is to purchase 2 of his books.
  - Letter to John Edward Gray?, 1843 November 23; Mangles, James
  - Letter to [John E. Gray], Nov. 27, 1843; 5-1/4x3-1/2; Clarke, William Branwhite, 1798-1878
    A.L.S. 1p. Will call upon him tomorrow.
  - Letter to John Edward Gray, 1844; The Horticultural Society.
  - Letter to Mrs. [Maria Emma] Gray, Jan. 7, 1844; 7x5; Fellows, Charles, Sir, 1799-1860
    A.L.S. 2p. Accepts invitation, if still needed.
  - Letter to Mrs Hawes, 1844 June 5; Gray, John Edward, 1800-1875
  - Letter to [John E. Gray], Aug. 30, 1844; 7-1/4x4-1/2; Bromfield, William Arnold, 1801-1851
    A.L.S. 4p. Gives him directions.
  - Letter to [John E.] Gray, Oct. 12, 1844; 7x4-1/2; Fellows, Charles, Sir, 1799-1860.
    A.L.S. 2p. Will be too happy to do him a favor.
  - Letter to John Edward Gray?, 1844 October 28; Hodgkin, Thomas, 1798-1866
  - Letter to [John E.] Gray, Nov. 19, 1844; 5-1/4x3-1/2; Schomburgk, Robert H. (Robert Hermann), Sir, 1804-1865
    A.L.S. 2p. Asks for directions from Mrs. Gray, since his have been misdirections.
  - Letter to John Edward Gray, 1844 December 7; Smith, Thomas Southwood
  - Letter to J[ohn] E. Gray, Dec. 14, 1844; 7x4-1/2; Brockedon, William, 1787-1854
    A.L.S. 2p. Introduces a man who wishes to present a carp to the museum.
  - Letter to J[ohn] E. Gray, London, Jan. 13, 1845; 7-1/2x4-1/2; Nuttall, Thomas, 1786-1859
    Rainhill, A.L.S. 1p. and add. Asks for several copies of the sketch which he will pick up when he visits London in the Spring.
  - Letter to B[enjamin?] Smith, April 12, 1845; 7x4-1/2; Eastlake, Charles Lock, Sir, 1793-1865
    A.L.S. 1p. Acknowledges letter.
  - Letter to Mrs. [Maria Emma] Gray, April 30, 1845; 6-3/4x4-1/2; Adamson, John, 1787-1855
    A.L.S. 1p. and enc. of 1p. Encloses a sonnett.
  - Letter to Mrs. John Edward Gray, 1845 May 8; Richardson, John, Sir, 1787-1865
  - Letter to [John E. Gray], June 6, 1845; 5-1/4x3-1/2; Bonomi, Joseph, 1796-1878
    A.L. 2p. Incomplete. Will exchange birds.
  - Letter to [John E.] Gray, June 22, 1845; 7x4-1/2; Children, John George, 1777-1852
    A.L.S. 1p. Accepts invitation to dinner.
  - Letter to [John E. Gray], July 12, 1845; 7x5; Blainville, Henri Marie Ducrotay, 1777-1850
    A.L.S. 3p. In French. Friendly letter. Refers to a fossil.
  - Letter to Mrs. [Maria Emma] Gray, July 19, 1845; 7-3/4x4-3/4; Thompson, Thomas Perronet, 1783-1869
    A.L.S. 3p. Botanical matters.
  - Letter to Ph[ilip] Barker Webb, Godalming, Surrey, Aug. 10, 1845; 9-3/4x7-3/4; Moquin-Tandon, [Horace Bénédict Alfred], 1804-1863.
    Toulouse, A.L.S. 3p. and add. In French. Concerning the study of plants.
  - Letter to [John] Edward Gray, 24 August, 1845; Hooker, William Jackson, Sir, 1785-1865
    Kew,... Sir Joseph Dalton, 1817-1911. I. [Gray, John Edward], 1800-1875.
  - Letter to John Edward Gray, 1845 September 23; Miers, John, 1789-1879
  - Letter to [John E. Gray], Oct. 22, 1845; 7-1/4x4-1/2; Clouston, Charles
    A.L.S. 3p. Concerning natural history specimens.
  - Letter to Mrs. [Maria Emma] Gray, London, Nov. 12, 1845; 7-1/2x5-1/2; Endlicher, Cécile
    Kerme, A.L.S. 3p. and add. In French. Introduces a young man on his way to America.
  - Hieroglyph to John Edward Gray, Feb. 2, 1846; 7-1/4x4-1/2; An, J. Y.
    D. 1p. and add.
  - Letter to J[ohn] E. Gray, April 2, 1846; 4x2-1/2; Berkeley, Miles Joseph, 1803-1889
    A.L.S. 1p. Forwards a shell to the British museum.
  - Letter to Mrs John Edward Gray, 1846 May 6; Praetorius, Dr
    Letter written in third person
  - Letter to Mrs. John Edward Gray, 1846 May 8; Taylor, Edward
    Written in third person
  - Letter to [John E. Gray], May 12, 1846; 7-1/4x4-1/2; Buckland, William, 1781-1856
    A.L.S. 2p. Concerning a fish.
  - Letter to John J. Bennett, May 16, 1846; 7x4-1/2; Beaufoy, Henry
    A.L. in 3rd.P. 1p. Refuses invitation.
  - Letter to J[ohn] J. Bennett, May 23, 1846; 3x4-1/4; Anderson, William, 1766-1846
    Chelsea, A.L.S. 1p. Cannot attend meeting of the Linnean society, due to his age.
  - Letter to J[ohn] E. Gray, June 12, 1846; 7x4-1/4; Airy, George Biddell, Sir, 1801-1892
    Greenwich, A.L.S. 1p. Introduces Peter Andreas Hansen.
  - Letter to [John E. Gray], June 22, 1846; 7x4-1/2; Baird, William, 1803-1872
    Kelso, A.L.S. 3p. Will come to London. Friendly Letter.
  - Letter to [John E. Gray], June 25, 1846; 7-1/4x4-1/2; Bamston, George
    Tadousac, A.L.S. 3p. Sends seals and other natural history objects from Canada.
  - Letter to J[ohn] E. Gray, June 27, 1846; 9-3/4x8; Holmes, Francis Simmons, 1815-1882
    London; Charleston, A.L.S. 1p. Proposes the exchange of shells.
  - Letter to J[ohn] E. Gray, London, July 14, 1846; 7x4-1/2; Copeland, George M.
    Woolwich, A.L.S. 3p. and add. Concerning birds.
  - Letter to J[ohn] E. Gray, July 14, 1846; 7-3/4x4-3/4; Müller, Johannes, 1801-1858
    A.L.S. 2p. Fears the items were left among his brother's papers.
  - Letter to J[ohn] E. Gray, July 16, 1846; 8x5; Müller, Johannes, 1801-1858
    A.L.S. 1p. Thanks for check.
  - Letter to [John E. Gray], Aug. 15, 1846; 10x8; Holbrook, John Edwards, 1794-1871
    Charleston, S.D., A.L.S. 1p. Has forwarded him publication. Plans of additional work on fishes of the South.
  - Letter to [John E.] Gray, Sept. 1, 1846; 7x5; Bunsen, Robert Wilhelm Eberhard von, 1811-1899
    A.L.in 3rd. P. 2p. and add. Has forwarded the publication to Berlin.
  - Letter to [John] Edw[ard] Gray, Oct. 20, 1846; 4-1/2x3-1/2; Carpenter, William Hookham, 1792-1866
    A.L.S. 1p. Is busy Thursday and Friday, but hopes Saturday will suit him.
  - Letter to [John E. Gray], Oct. 24, 1846; 9x7-3/4; Valenciennes, Achille, 1794-1865
    A.L.S. 1p. In French. Friendly, farewell letter.
  - Letter to John Edward Gray, 1846 November 3; Longman, William
  - Letter to John Edward Gray?, 1846 December 13; Jervis, Swynfen
  - Letter to [John E.] Gray, London, Dec. 26, 1846; 8-1/4 x 5-1/2; Michellin, Fr.
    L.S. 3p. and add. In French. Concerning natural history. Refers to Agassiz.
  - Letter to [John E. Gray], Jan. 31, 1847; 9-1/2x7-1/2; Agassiz, Louis, 1807-1873
    Boston, A.L.S. 2p. In French. Concerning his collections for a natural history museum.
  - Letter to [John E. Gray], Feb. 10, 1847; 10x8-1/2; Grey, William
    A.L.S. 2p. Concerning the exchange of insects etc.
  - Letter to [John E. Gray], Feb. 19, 1847; 5x8; Hoeven, Jan van der, 1802-1868
    Leiden, A.L.S. 1p. Introduces a relative who would like to visit in the British Museum.
  - Letter to John Edward Gray, 1847? March Thursday; Worsaae, Jens Jakob Asmussen, 1821-1885
  - Letter to [John E.] Gray, March 26, 1847; 7-1/4x4-1/2; Worsaee, Jens Jacob Asmussen, 1821-1885
    A.L.S. 1p. Offers birds for sale and exchange.
  - Letter to Mrs. John Edward Gray, 1847 March 28; Phillips, Henry W.
  - Letter to John Edward Gray, 1847 May 13; Hill, Arthur
  - Letter to [John E.] Gray, April 11, 1847; 6-1/4x5; Bourcier, Jules
    London, A.L.S. 1p. In French. Accepts invitation.
  - Letter to J[ohn] E. Gray, London, April 24, 1847; 9-1/2x7-1/4; Dana, James Dwight, 1813-1895
    New Haven, A.L.S. 2p. and add. Concerning corals.
  - Letter to Mrs John Edward Gray, third person, 1847 May 19; Osler, William, Sir, 1849-1919
  - Letter to ----, June 10, 1847; 8-3/4x6-3/4; Moulines, Charles des
    A.L.S. 4p. In French. Hopes to meet Gray. Discusses questions of natural history. Refers to Lyell, the Geological and Linnean societies, Agassiz, and French societies and men.
  - Letter to John Edward Gray, 1847 June 10?; Norwich, E.
  - Letter to John Edw[ard] Gray, London, July 3, 1847; 9-3/4x8-1/2; Müller, Johannes, 1801-1858
    Berlin, A.L.S. 2p. and add. In German.
  - Letter to [John E. Gray], July 14, 1847; 9-1/2x7; Delaz, Julian M.
    Liege, A.L.S. 1p. Asks for position in the museum if a vacancy should occur in natural history.
  - Letter to [John E.] Gray, July 28, 1847; 5-3/4x3-1/2; Schomburgk, Robert H. (Robert Hermann), Sir, 1804-1865
    A.L.S. 4p. Forwards Trosehel material and asks his opinion on it. On same sheet is: Gray to Schomburgk; Aug. 1, 18476.
  - Letter to [Sir Robert Hermann Schomburgk], Aug. 1, 1847; 5-3/4x3-1/2; Gray, John Edward, 1800-1875
    A.L.S. 1p. Draft. Concerning Trochel's letter. On same sheet as: Schomburgk to Gray; July 28, 1847.
  - Letter to John Edward Gray, 1847 August 2; Lawes, Edward
  - Letter to J[ohn] E. Gray, Aug. 15, 1847; 6x3-3/4; Esmark, Lauritz
    A.L.S. 1p. Accepts invitation.
  - Letter to [John E. Gray], Sept. 21, 1847; 7-1/4x4-1/2; Curzon, Robert, 1810-1873.
    A.L.S. 1p. and add. Forwards wild sheep specimens.
  - Letter to [John E.] Gray, Sept. 23, 1847; 7x4-1/2; Schomburgk, Robert H. (Robert Hermann), Sir, 1804-1865
    A.L.S. 2p. Sends fishes and birds to the museum.
  - Letter to [John E.] Gray, Oct. 2, 1847; 7x4-1/4; Blainville, Henri Marie Ducrotay, 1777-1850
    A.L.S. 2p. In French. Concerning explorers who collect natural history for museums.
  - Letter to J[ohn] E. Gray, Nov. 2, 1847; 9x7-1/4; Cocks, W. P.
    Falmouth, A.L.S. 2p. Inquires as to the identity of an animal, which he draws.
  - Letter to [John E.] Gray, March, 1847?; 7-1/4x4-1/2; Worsaee, Jens Jacob Asmussen, 1821-1885
    A.L.S. 1p. Inquires about purchase of exchange of birds.
  - Letter to John Edward Gray, 1848 January 17; Weekes, Henry
  - Letter to [John E. Gray], Jan. 19, 1848; 7-1/4x4-3/4; Donaldson, Thomas Leverton, 1795-1855
    A.L.S. 1p. Thanks for favor.
  - Letter to [John E. Gray], Jan. 28, 1848; 7x4-1/4; Dundas, James Whitley Deans, Sir, 1785-1862
    A.L.S. 2p., seal. Has passed the request on.
  - Letter to [John E. Gray], Feb. 7, 1848; 7-1/4x4-1/2; Belcher, Edward, Sir, 1799-1877
    A.L.S. 2p. Asks a favor.
  - Letter to John Edward Gray?, 1848 February 18; Smyth, W. H., (William Henry), 1788-1865
  - Letter to Mrs. [Maria Emma] Gray, Feb. 28, 1848; 7-1/2x4-1/2; Bennett, John Joseph, 1801-1876
    A.L.S. 1p. Cannot dine with her today.
  - Letter to J[ohn] E. Gray, March 1, 1848; 4-1/2x3-1/2; Forster, John, 1812-1876
    A.L.S. 2p. Is sorry he could not visit him.
  - Letter to John Edward Gray, 1848 March 1; Hosking, William
  - Letter to J[ohn] E. Gray, March 15, 1848; 6-1/2x4; Barclay, Andrew Whyte, 1817-1884
  - Letter to J[ohn] E. Gray, May 9, 1848; 7-1/2x4-3/4; Metropolitan Improvement Society of London
    Printed L. filled in in ms. 1p. and add. Announces date of meeting.
  - Letter to Mrs. [Maria Emma] Gray, May 19, 1848; 10x7-3/4; Forshall, Josiah, 1795-1863
    A.L.S. 1p. Thanks for publication for the museum.
  - Letter to W[illia]m Ellis, June 11, 1848; 7-1/4x5; Combe, George, 1788-1858
    Edinburgh, A.L.S. 1p. Concerning education.
  - Letter to [John E. Gray], June 21, 1848; 7-1/4x4-1/2; Dillwyn, Lewis Weston, 1778-1855
    Tenby, A.L.S. 2p. Concerning a large hammer-head shark.
  - Letter to R. [John E.] Gray, London, July 12, 1848; 8-3/4x5-1/2; Esmark, Lauritz
    Christiania, Denmark, A.L.S. 3p., end. and add. Has been ill. Concerning fishes.
  - Letter to J[ohn] E. Gray, Sept. 4, 1848; 4-3/4x3-3/4; Grant, Robert Edmond, 1793-1874
  - Letter to J[ohn] E. Gray, Oct. 12, 1848; 6-3/4x4-3/4; Brightwell, Thomas
    Norwich, A.L.S. 1p. Will be home next week and the museum will be open.
  - Letter to J[ohn] E. Gray, Oct. 29, 1848; 7x4-1/4; Spence, William, 1783-1860
    A.L.S. 3p. Forwards check for purchase of plate of his portrait and prints which he wishes Gray to keep to give to persons who may want such prints.
  - Letter to [Mrs. Maria Emma Gray], Oct. 30, 1848; 7-1/2x4-1/2; Stuart, Daniel
    Yarmouth, A.L.S. 2p. Thanks for work. Sends sketch by his daughter.
  - Letter to J[ohn] E. Gray, Dec. 6, 1848; 4-1/2x3-1/2; Bowerbank, James Scott, 1797-1877
    A.L.S. 3p. Concerning the expense for an election.
  - Letter to J[ohn] E. Gray, Dec. 16, 1848; 7x4-1/2; Cuming, Hugh, 1791-1865
    A.L.S. 1p. Has reptiles ready for inspection.
  - Letter to [John E. Gray], Jan., 1849; 10x7-3/4; Conrad, Timothy Abbott, 1803-1877
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p. and sketch of mollusk shells. Introduces Robert E. Peterson. Concerning shells.
  - Letter to [John E. Gray?], Jan. 16, 1849; 3-1/2x8-1/4; Baird, Spencer Fullerton, 1823-1887
    Carlisle, Penna., A.L.S. 1p. Certifies that skins from Oregon by Dr. Townsend are excellent.
  - Letter to Mrs. [Maria Emma] Gray, Jan. 25, 1849; 6-3/4x4-1/2; Colnaghi, Dominic Paul, 1790-1879
    A.L.S. 1p. Refuses invitation.
  - Letter to [John E. Gray], Feb. 6, 1849; 7-1/4x4-1/2; Forshall, Josiah, 1795-1863
    A.L.S. 1p. Will help if possible.
  - Letter to Mrs. [Maria Emma Gray], May 8, 1849; 7-1/2x4-1/2; Klipstein, A.
    London, A.L.S. 1p. In French. Accepts invitation, if she stays in London that long.
  - Letter to Mrs. [Maria Emma Gray], May 9, 1849; 7-1/2x4-1/2; Kaup
    A.L.S. 1p. Hopes to see them before he leaves London.
  - Letter to [John E. Gray], May 15, 1849; 10x8-1/2; Jeude, T. G. van Lidth de
    Utrecht, A.L.S. 1p. In Dutch.
  - Letter to J. Russell, 15 May, 1849; Gray, John Edward, 1800-1875
    [London], ALS 2p. From British Museum. Describes location of Nineveh antiquities; will make those not on display available upon request.
  - Letter to J. Russell, Gray, John Edward, 1800-1875
  - Leter to Mrs John Edward Gray, 1849 May 18; Wolf, Mr
  - Letter to J[ohn] E. Gray, London, May 18, 1849; 8-3/4x7-1/2; Herklots, J. A.
    Leiden, A.L.S. 1p. Asks for payment of an exchange, of invertebrate animals.
  - Letter to L. B. Stair, May 31, 1849; 7-3/4x5; Boone, William
    A.L.S. 2p. Concerning a work on the grouse.
  - Letter to John Edward Gray, British Museum, June 13, 1849; 8x5-1/2; Henry, Joseph, 1797-1878
    Washington, A.L.S. 4p. Asks for information to aid in the plans for the Smithsonian institution. Refers to A. D. Bache.
  - Letter to [John E. Gray], June 24, 1849; 10x7-1/2; Saucerotte, Antoine Constant, 1805-1884
    Stuttgart, A.L.S. 1p., end. Recommends a friend.
  - Letter to John Edward Grey (Gray), 1849 July 8; Herbert, John Rogers
  - Letter to [John E.] Gray, July 14, 1849; 8-1/4x5; Everest, R.
    A.L.S. 1p. Forwards parcel containing Indian snakes.
  - Letter to [John E. Gray], Aug. 10, 1849; 9x7-1/2; Castelnau, Francis, comte de, 1812-1880
    Bahia, Brazil, A.L.S. 2p. In French. Forwards natural history specimens.
  - Letter to Mrs John Edward Gray, 1849 August 29; Kenyon, J.B.
  - Letter to Mr and Mrs John Edward Gray, 1849 September 4; Neill, Patrick, 1796-1851
  - Letter to Mrs John Edward Gray, 1849 September 12; Neill, Patrick, 1796-1851
  - Letter to [John E. Gray], Sept. 18, 1849; 8x5; Cunningham, James
    Edinburgh, A.L.S. 4p. Concerning his collection of shells.
  - Letter to J[ohn] E. Gray, Oct. 20, 1849; 7-1/4x4-3/4; Taylor's, R.and J.E., printing office
    London, A.L.S.: W. Askham. 1p. Concerning the proposed calendar for the museum.
  - Letter to Mrs John Edward Gray, 1849 November 9; Martin, Thomas Byam, Sir
  - Letter to [John E.] Gray, Dec. 20, 1849; 6-3/4x4; Blainville, Henri Marie Ducrotay, 1777-1850
    A.L.S. 2p. In French. Concerning natural history. Concerning mollusks.
  - Letter to J[ohn] Ed[ward] Gray, London, Jan. 2, 1850; 6x3-1/2; Bonaparte, Charles Lucien Jules Laurent, Prince de Canino, 1803-1857
    Leyden, A.L.S. 3p. and add. Asks him to print works. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to Edward J(sic) Gray, 1850 January 7; Krantz, August
  - Letter to [John E.] Gray, Jan. 16, 1850; 7x4-1/2; Baly, William, 1814-1861
    A.L. in 3rd.P. 1p. Hopes to attend the conversations.
  - Letter to John Edward Gray, 1850 January 21; Norris, Edwin
  - Letter to John Edward Gray, 1850 February 3; Russell, Arthur
  - Letter to E. G. [John E.] Gray, Feb. 7, 1850; 9-3/4x7-1/2; Krantz, August
    Bonn, A.L.S. 1p. and add. Has forwarded specimens.